{
    "id": "15be93913f804c6bb1edc9af9430abe7",
    "title": "Figures Of Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Let him be rich and weary.",
            "description": "Paradox is a statement that seems absurd or self-contradictory but may actually be true.",
            "answers": [
                "Paradox",
                "Oxymoron",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "So innocent arch, so cunningly simple.",
            "description": "When two contradictory qualities of the same thing are mentioned at once, it is called oxymoron.",
            "answers": [
                "Antithesis",
                "Oxymoron",
                "metaphor"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "All the perfumes of Arabia will not sweeten this little hand.",
            "description": "When a statement is made emphatic by overstatement, it is called hyperbole.",
            "answers": [
                "Hyperbole",
                "Oxymoron",
                "Antithesis"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "All the world is a stage.",
            "description": "A metaphor is an implied simile. It makes an indirect comparison.",
            "answers": [
                "Metaphor",
                "Paradox"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The mountains sing together, the hills rejoice and clap hands.",
            "description": "When inanimate objects are spoken of as having life, it becomes personification.",
            "answers": [
                "Antithesis",
                "Personification",
                "Metaphor"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Many are called, but few are chosen.",
            "description": "When opposite ideas are placed side by side for emphasis it is called antithesis.",
            "answers": [
                "Antithesis",
                "Euphemism",
                "Personification"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Men may come and men may go, but I go on for ever.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Oxymoron",
                "Personification",
                "Antithesis"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The child is the father of man.",
            "description": "An epigram is a saying which excites, surprises or grabs attention.",
            "answers": [
                "Epigram",
                "Oxymoron",
                "Simile"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Fools rush in where angels fear to tread.",
            "description": "An epigram is a saying which excites, surprises or grabs attention.",
            "answers": [
                "Irony",
                "Epigram",
                "Alliteration"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I desired my dust to be mingled with yours.",
            "description": "When a statement is made emphatic by overstatement it is called hyperbole.",
            "answers": [
                "Hyperbole",
                "Epigram",
                "Antithesis"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "An ambassador is an honest man who lies abroad for the good of his country.",
            "description": "When there is more than one meaning in the same word, it is called pun.",
            "answers": [
                "Euphemism",
                "Pun",
                "Hyperbole"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The soldier fights for glory and a shilling a day!",
            "description": "When the ideas are presented in a descending order, it is called anticlimax.",
            "answers": [
                "Climax",
                "Anticlimax",
                "Pun"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}